<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-21T11:23:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">MEDICI</title><subtitle>Description</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Next Chapter in Our Journey</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-next-chapter-in-our-journey/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Next Chapter in Our Journey" /><published>2018-01-18T16:15:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-18T16:15:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-next-chapter-in-our-journey</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-next-chapter-in-our-journey/">&lt;p&gt;Five years ago, hosting the first ever Money20/20 event, we could see something coming… a confluence of industries, the adoption of mobile and open platforms, a focus on new business models empowered by technology… today we call it FinTech!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the years since, we continued the journey with Let’s Talk Payments (LTP), a curated insights platform that today has more than 100,000 subscribers and millions of annual views globally. LTP quickly became the world’s #1 digital destination for FinTech trends and analysis. We thank each of you for your support along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MEDICI knowledge portal was a natural extension of LTP, together offering proprietary research and data, and expertly organized so that the complex maze of FinTech could be navigated with ease. This shared resource has become FinTech’s digital watering hole, a place where financial institutions and startups identify and accelerate game-changing collaborations, facilitated by investors, accelerators and hundreds of innovation programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the FinTech space has grown and undergone rapid change, so have we. And as we reflect on these changes, we want to make sure our brand and offerings continue to serve the mission we have always believed in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enabling all FinTech stakeholders to innovate at scale to further our common agenda of creating global economic impact.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are reading this note, you are already our partner in this mission. THANK YOU!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have encouraged us to keep going when the road was uncharted, to change course when the approach wasn’t clear, to stop trying when the effort was futile. And most importantly, you’re the reason we continue to share the most accurate observations and insights every single day, rain or shine, during Christmas or Diwali, in hurricane or monsoon, with conviction in our mission and the trust of our audience (that’s you!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This mission, which has always been at the heart of everything we do, is best served by consolidating our brand, insights, and products into a single name and a consolidated offering:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/MEDICI_logo_withtagline.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MEDICI_logo_withtagline.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;￼MEDICI represents our entire FinTech industry… the financial institutions; insurance companies; technology giants; established FinTech companies; 10,000+ FinTech startups; hundreds of investors, accelerators, incubators, challenges, hackathons, events, innovation programs; and of course our 200,000+ email subscribers and social media followers. Innovators from every FinTech segment around the world… all under the same tent, collaborating and inspiring the booming FinTech space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of you have worked tirelessly alongside us to build this new industry together. Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is our sincerest hope that this next chapter in our journey presents new opportunities for you to make your voice heard, your products known, and your impact felt across the FinTech landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aditya Khurjekar, with Amit Goel&lt;/strong&gt;
Founders, MEDICI (Formerly Let’s Talk Payments or LTP)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P.S.&lt;/strong&gt; Excited to offer you the summary of our latest report: &lt;strong&gt;2018 State of Global FinTech&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;/state-of-fintech-2018/&quot;&gt;Click here for your free report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Five years ago, hosting the first ever Money20/20 event, we could see something coming… a confluence of industries, the adoption of mobile and open platforms, a focus on new business models empowered by technology… today we call it FinTech!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Open Banking Story – MEDICI Roundtable Discussion</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-open-banking-story-medici-roundtable-discussion/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Open Banking Story – MEDICI Roundtable Discussion" /><published>2018-01-18T16:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-18T16:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-open-banking-story-medici-roundtable-discussion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-open-banking-story-medici-roundtable-discussion/">&lt;p&gt;MEDICI has been at the center of several discussions on FinTech trends and developments around the globe. While there are a lot of events, conferences and talks happening around the world, the commercial angle of these discussions leads to a lot of noise, because of which there has been a real gap when it comes to the quality and depth of insights that come out of such discussion. MEDICI’s newest initiative – a roundtable with some of the select thought leaders across the ecosystem – is a proactive step which aims at bridging this gap and bringing out the best of insights stemming from both the industry side as well as the observatory side. By having a small number of panelists sitting together and brainstorming on key areas, – without having the marketing and PR perspective around the discussion – we look forward to bringing out some fresh, deep, and holistic insights for the FinTech community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first in the series of many more to come, MEDICI’s roundtable on &lt;strong&gt;Open Banking&lt;/strong&gt; saw some of the prominent thought leaders coming together at our mini-innovation lab and discussing the nuances of open banking in the wake EU’s PSD2 implementation on January 13. Here is the list of panelists that participated in the roundtable discussion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Salil Ravindran:&lt;/strong&gt; Global Lead of Digital Banking Center of Excellence, ‎Oracle&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diwakar Mandal:&lt;/strong&gt; Senior Industry Analyst, LTP&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bhushan Sonkusare:&lt;/strong&gt; Vice President of Financial Services (FS) Advisory, Digital Business Transformation (DBT) &amp;amp; FinTech, ‎Sapient&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rajat Deshpande:&lt;/strong&gt; CEO, Finbox&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ricardo Geromel:&lt;/strong&gt; Author of bestseller &lt;em&gt;“Billionaires,”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Forbes&lt;/em&gt; columnist &amp;amp; Head of Investments of StartSe&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amit Goel:&lt;/strong&gt; CIO &amp;amp; Co-Founder, LTP&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chiranth Patil:&lt;/strong&gt; Angel Investor&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the two-hour-long discussion, we covered the entire spectrum of open banking in depth from multiple perspectives – from that of a bank, FinTech, TechFin, merchants, and customers. In this article, we present some of the key themes that were discussed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-psd2-is-it-the-same-as-open-banking&quot;&gt;What is PSD2? Is it the same as open banking?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PSD2 and open banking – though spoken about in the same context – are essentially two different initiative. PSD2, which is the revised payment service directive by EU, brings clear guidelines and national laws to the EU countries which mandate banks – based on customer’s consent – to comply with the demand of opening their APIs and customer data for licensed third-party players (TPPs). The EU member states have implemented PSD2 in their national regulations with effect from January 13, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, open banking is an industry-led initiative by the Competition and Markets Authority (CMA) in the UK, with the nine largest banks being mandated to open up their APIs. The banks were given a deadline of January 13, 2018, by which they were expected to be ready with their open APIs. As of today, only five of these nine banks are ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-did-the-open-banking-launch-on-january-13-go-relatively-unnoticed-and-was-not-celebrated-as-one-of-the-biggest-landmarks-in-the-banking-history-should-have-been&quot;&gt;Why did the open banking launch on January 13 go relatively unnoticed and was not celebrated as one of the biggest landmarks in the banking history should have been?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salil attributed this to the unpreparedness of banks from a compliance perspective. Though the dates were set long ago, it was only a year ago that the banks began to realize the granular nitty-gritties of this initiative including data sharing, security frameworks, consent architecture, authentication challenges, etc. In hindsight, the January 13 deadline was more of a checking-the-box event, and thus went unnoticed. We will need to wait longer for a comprehensive open banking rollout as the banks have been given another deadline of 18 months to meet the new security and data standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;consent-for-data-sharing--authentication-as-the-pivotal-blocks-in-the-open-banking-puzzle&quot;&gt;Consent for data sharing &amp;amp; authentication as the pivotal blocks in the open banking puzzle.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The underlying idea of open banking is to place the consent and choice in the hands of the customers. The onus lies on the regulators, stakeholder groups (CMA), and the banks to design a robust consent architecture at a fine-grained level. There also have been ongoing measures for eliminating some of the conflicts with GDPR on the P2P payment data front, where the consent of not one but both the parties is required. So far, there has not been a robust system built yet and there is still much work left to be done in this space before we get a clarity on the consent framework. This also calls for an increased effort on privacy, security, and fraud prevention aspects of data sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going beyond consent, a robust and channel-independent multi-factor authentication remains one of the crucial building blocks for the open banking experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-the-banks-most-anxious-about-in-this-open-banking-scenario&quot;&gt;What are the banks most anxious about in this open banking scenario?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 
With a growing number of PISPs, the biggest anxieties are around revenue loss and the prospect of losing a chunk of customer relationships to the FinTechs/TechFins. Ricardo highlighted that the real challenge for the big banks is not the technology, but the people and their perception towards change. Also, banks have never been able to fully utilize their data resources, and once the data is made available to TechFins/FinTechs, they will be in a better position to leverage this data to come up with better services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bhushan touched upon some of the basic challenges traditional banks face. Many of the banks, who are still tangled in the complexities of legacy modernization have a huge task ahead of them to be able to match the modern technological and data standards the open banking demands. There is a huge cultural gap between the banks and the Amazons/Googles of the world which – along with the superior tech/resource/data leverage – gives these tech giants a huge advantage over banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;however-there-are-many-opportunities-for-banks-to-re-invent-themselves&quot;&gt;However, there are many opportunities for banks to re-invent themselves.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks are the smartest incumbents. Many of them have reacted to the FinTech disruption quite early on. They were quick to identify the collaborative potential of FinTech, while also working on launching their own next-gen experiences. E.g. SBI, one of India’s largest and oldest traditional bank, has recently launched a digital bank called &lt;strong&gt;“Yono.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open banking provides a rich opportunity for banks to re-invent themselves, foster collaborative innovation by being a key provider as well as consumer of open APIs, and explore newer business models – e.g. marketplace/distributor/BaaS. There have been discussions around whether the banks in the EU will take a progressive step and innovate, or if they’ll just comply with PSD2 on a bare minimum level. While we expect most of the banks to take the former route, some banks who take the later route are likely to lose their grip on customer relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks can easily obtain the AISP license and can leverage the APIs of their rival banks using their customer’s consent – where their customers have additional accounts – to understand certain aspects of their business. E.g. HSBC bank is already doing something similar through its partnership with an account aggregator, Bud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will also give banks a deeper insight into their customer’s financial lives which will enable them to understand – and thus service – their needs better. This, however, again falls under the zone of uncertainty where the guidelines and nitty-gritty regarding data sharing are yet to be clearly put in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-banking-may-pave-way-for--not-a-fintech-but--a-techfin-monopoly&quot;&gt;Open banking may pave way for – not a FinTech, but – a TechFin monopoly.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 
With their stronghold on customer experience and data/tech/resource leverage, tech giants such as Google, Apple, and Ant Financial have a strong case of emerging as the next big invaders and driving the customer relationships away from the banks by consuming their APIs and building services on top. Rajat pointed out a possibility that the competition may begin with collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tech giants, such as Amazon, Google may begin to collaborate with banks through their APIs and over time, will look to develop some of the key domain expertise in a very stealthy way by leveraging the crucial customer data which they have always considered to be sacrosanct. However, some time down the line, there might be an inflection point where once they have developed enough expertise, they may take the lead and drive the collaboration on their own terms or simply declare themselves as a competitor. In such a situation, banks who adapt to the situation by tweaking their business models and serving as a provider of banking service modules will go a long way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the data leverage that these tech giants enjoy will eventually lead to a &lt;strong&gt;data-driven monopoly&lt;/strong&gt;, which will make it difficult for other players – banks and FinTechs – to compete with them. With the high information density of this data and a plethora of touchpoints, this will enable these tech giants to read through the financial lives of their customers. Any of these players getting to such a data monopoly stage will be ready to dominate the financial services stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-may-see-the-emergence-of-newer-business-models-in-the-banking-space&quot;&gt;We may see the emergence of newer business models in the banking space.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks can adopt several newer business models. E.g. Aggregator, marketplace, banking-as-a-service, etc. Out of these, the most immediately realizable business model looks to be the one where banks play the role of a distributor/marketplace for FinTech solutions. A classic example is Starling Bank, which provides best-in-class services financial services to its customers by means of a plug-and-play collaborative model with leading players from various FinTech segments, embedding their services on its own platform – e.g. TransferWise for remittance, Moneybox for PFM, etc. This is a classic case of the much-revered unbundling of banks being followed by re-bundling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This business model makes the most sense in a market like India with the emergence of payment banks. Payment banks have a limited portfolio of offerings, which they can expand through similar partnership arrangements. E.g. Paytm and ICICI coming together to provide micro-loans for a ‘buy now, pay later’ use case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;to-sum-up-pros--cons-of-open-banking&quot;&gt;To sum up: Pros &amp;amp; cons of open banking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consumers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pros
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Dashboarding/visualization of their financial activities&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Better choice for services&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Enhanced transparency&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bundled services&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cons
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Privacy&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Data security&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Uncertainty over fraud/error accountability&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Merchants:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pro
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Access to rich consumer data&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Additional revenue streams by going deep into payments&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Con
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Compliance overhead costs for data sharing norms&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pro
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;News business models&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;New revenue streams&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deep insights into customer needs&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cons
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Revenue loss&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Disintermediation of customer relationships&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Higher churn rates&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;High cost of change management&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Impact on profit margins of smaller banks&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="open banking" /><summary type="html">MEDICI has been at the center of several discussions on FinTech trends and developments around the globe. While there are a lot of events, conferences and talks happening around the world, the commercial angle of these discussions leads to a lot of noise, because of which there has been a real gap when it comes to the quality and depth of insights that come out of such discussion. MEDICI’s newest initiative – a roundtable with some of the select thought leaders across the ecosystem – is a proactive step which aims at bridging this gap and bringing out the best of insights stemming from both the industry side as well as the observatory side. By having a small number of panelists sitting together and brainstorming on key areas, – without having the marketing and PR perspective around the discussion – we look forward to bringing out some fresh, deep, and holistic insights for the FinTech community.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily Review: Why Regulation Is Crucial to FinTech’s Future</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/daily-review-why-regulation-is-crucial-to-fintechs-future/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily Review: Why Regulation Is Crucial to FinTech’s Future" /><published>2018-01-18T15:30:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-18T15:30:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/daily-review-why-regulation-is-crucial-to-fintechs-future</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/daily-review-why-regulation-is-crucial-to-fintechs-future/">&lt;p&gt;Being home to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://letstalkpayments.com/china-is-home-to-the-largest-fintech-unicorns-in-the-world/&quot;&gt;largest unicorns in the world&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://letstalkpayments.com/china-leapfrogs-the-world-in-fostering-innovation/&quot;&gt;China has been continuously leapfrogging the world in fostering rapid technological innovation adoption&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://letstalkpayments.com/fintech-in-china-a-53-point-summary/&quot;&gt;Dozens of reasons for China to become the most innovative hub&lt;/a&gt; have been enriched with another one – its &lt;a href=&quot;https://letstalkpayments.com/daily-review-china-applies-creativity-imagination-to-business-financing-powering-emerging-industries/&quot;&gt;own experience&lt;/a&gt; that led China’s finance and tech professionals to learn the key to sustainable innovation. Regulations are not seen as crippling to the opportunities presented by the tech community, but rather reasonable safeguards developed from a colorful experience and the need to put innovation on the rails of massive adoption. Sophisticated frameworks around the FinTech industry will add to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://letstalkpayments.com/five-factors-dramatic-rise-chinas-fintech-2017/&quot;&gt;factors that will drive the dramatic rise of China’s FinTech&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pick-1-freedom-at-a-price-why-regulation-is-crucial-to-fintechs-future&quot;&gt;Pick #1. ‘Freedom at a Price’: Why Regulation Is Crucial to FinTech’s Future&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;China’s FinTech industry has seen Ponzi schemes and weak business models, and that about 100 online wealth management platforms in China went out of business in 2015-2016. Through a series of moves beginning January 2016, China’s government has tightened regulatory oversight of the FinTech space. It also went after FinTech firms that offered excessive and unsustainable returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Many of the new financial systems don’t have the safeguards,” said Edward Hartman, Co-founder of LegalZoom, who is also the entrepreneur-in-residence at Simon-Kucher &amp;amp; Partners, a global consulting firm, listing another area of concern. “And they’re enormously powerful.” He added that while FinTechs bring financial inclusion, regulation and oversight are essential to protect investors. “It’s freedom that comes at a price.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://knowledge.wharton.upenn.edu/article/freedom-that-comes-at-a-price-why-regulation-is-crucial-to-fintechs-future/&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pick-2-explaining-psd2-without-tlas-is-tough-by-starling-bank&quot;&gt;Pick #2. Explaining PSD2 Without TLAs Is Tough! (By Starling Bank)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the pros and cons for all the players in PSD2?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros and Cons for Consumers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+ Ability to consolidate all accounts in one place with continued protection under their product terms and conditions\
+ The choice of the most convenient internet or app interface to check their bank account details\
+ Direct integration of their bank account with merchant acquiring sites is convenient and practical\
– Lack of clarity of responsibility between PISPs (merchants) and the ASPSPs (banks) in the event of loss&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros and Cons for Merchants&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+ Reduced costs compared to card interchange\
+ Immediate settlement into merchants account\
+ Even greater direct relationship with the customer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros and Cons for Banks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+ Ability to position themselves as an AISP\
– Significant costs to change systems\
– Loss of screen time in front of consumer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.starlingbank.com/blog/explaining-psd2-without-tlas-tough/&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pick-3-introducing-our-powerful-new-geolocation-travel-insurance-by-revolut&quot;&gt;Pick #3. Introducing Our Powerful New Geolocation Travel Insurance (By Revolut)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does it work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.revolut.com/travel-insurance&quot;&gt;Pay-per-day Travel Insurance&lt;/a&gt; makes use of Revolut’s geolocation technology to pinpoint exactly where you are in the world and automatically turn on coverage for you when traveling.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Using your Revolut app, you can easily tailor your insurance policy to suit your needs, even if you’re already on the move. For example, you can extend your policy to include friends or family, or add cover for winter sports such as skiing or snowboarding, all at the tap of a button.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much does it cost?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“In true Revolut style, our Pay-per-Day Travel Insurance starts at less than £1 per day. On average, a Revolut user spends 13 days abroad per year, which means that Pay-per-Day Travel Insurance only costs £11.76!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who provides the cover?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Revolut works with leading underwriters, White Horse Insurance Ireland, part of the Thomas Cook Group, who are authorized and regulated by the Central Bank of Ireland.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.revolut.com/introducing-our-powerful-new-geolocation-travel-insurance/&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="fintech" /><category term="regulation" /><category term="travel insurance" /><category term="insurtech" /><summary type="html">Being home to the largest unicorns in the world, China has been continuously leapfrogging the world in fostering rapid technological innovation adoption. Dozens of reasons for China to become the most innovative hub have been enriched with another one – its own experience that led China’s finance and tech professionals to learn the key to sustainable innovation. Regulations are not seen as crippling to the opportunities presented by the tech community, but rather reasonable safeguards developed from a colorful experience and the need to put innovation on the rails of massive adoption. Sophisticated frameworks around the FinTech industry will add to the factors that will drive the dramatic rise of China’s FinTech.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why FinTech? Conversation with Ram Gopal, CEO of Barclays Bank India</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/why-fintech-conversation-with-ram-gopal-ceo-barclays-bank-india/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why FinTech? Conversation with Ram Gopal, CEO of Barclays Bank India" /><published>2018-01-18T15:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-18T15:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/why-fintech-conversation-with-ram-gopal-ceo-barclays-bank-india</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/why-fintech-conversation-with-ram-gopal-ceo-barclays-bank-india/">&lt;p&gt;In a conversation with Rise Mumbai as part of the Rise Mumbai FinTech Prodegree, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ram-gopal-19944723/&quot;&gt;Ram Gopal&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of Barclays Bank India, shares his vision on what FinTech and what is its core value for the developing and developed world, addressing series of questions about the financial services industry and its transformation over the years ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/eklktqLgYGI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why FinTech? Conversation with Ram Gopal, CEO, Barclays Bank India&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="fintech" /><summary type="html">In a conversation with Rise Mumbai as part of the Rise Mumbai FinTech Prodegree, Ram Gopal, CEO of Barclays Bank India, shares his vision on what FinTech and what is its core value for the developing and developed world, addressing series of questions about the financial services industry and its transformation over the years ahead.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sensory and Tracking Technologies Are the Key to IoT Proliferation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sensory-tracking-technologies-are-key-to-iot-proliferation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sensory and Tracking Technologies Are the Key to IoT Proliferation" /><published>2018-01-17T16:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-17T16:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sensory-tracking-technologies-are-key-to-iot-proliferation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sensory-tracking-technologies-are-key-to-iot-proliferation/">&lt;p&gt;Of all emerging technologies, executives believe the IoT will be the most important, ranking it above others such as artificial intelligence or robotics, Forbes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbespr/2018/01/16/business-is-embracing-internet-of-things-as-most-important-technology-says-new-study/#ff1824c41ff1&quot;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;. Some of the most recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/global-smart-cities-iot-technology-revenues-to-exceed-us60-billion-by-2026-300582127.html&quot;&gt;estimates&lt;/a&gt; suggest that IoT technology revenues across 12 key smart city technologies and verticals will grow from around $25 billion in 2017 to $62 billion in 2026 at an average growth rate of 11%. But the successful real-world impact of IoT depends on enabling infrastructure, such as sensory and tracking technologies, advanced analytical capabilities running on the new generation of processing power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.preparewithforesight.com/wearable-technology-disaster-response/&quot;&gt;Sensory technology is a particularly important and interesting field&lt;/a&gt;, developments in which have significant implications across industries. Sensory and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/288864&quot;&gt;tracking tech&lt;/a&gt; create real-time streams of invaluable data with a unique predictive potential. The wearables, trackers, and smart home devices that our lives are stuffed with create a constant stream of evolving data that allow companies to understand every moment in our lives and make a data-based assumption of the evolution of one’s needs, translating into the ability to tailor delivered services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Novel sensors and sensing systems will provide previously unimaginable insight into the condition of individuals and the built and natural worlds, positively impacting people, machines, and the environment,” &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.mit.edu/2017/future-of-sensory-technology-mit-nano-0522&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imes.mit.edu/research-staff-prof/brian-anthony/&quot;&gt;Brian W. Anthony&lt;/a&gt;, a principal research engineer at MIT and Director of the Advanced Manufacturing &amp;amp; Design Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, as sensory and tracking technology accumulates a significant amount of detailed information – whether commercial or personal device information – increasingly accurate patterns and predictions will be possible. Data analytics will become an even more critical function with the evolution of &lt;a href=&quot;http://mashable.com/2018/01/08/ibm-quantum-computer-ces-201i8/#1y75COLRmOq9&quot;&gt;hardware-powered machine learning and AI&lt;/a&gt;. For businesses, this would translate into cost-efficiency and the discovery of innovation avenues among other &lt;a href=&quot;https://letstalkpayments.com/applications-of-big-data-analytics-that-yield-most-value/&quot;&gt;critical implications&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;http://chemistry.mit.edu/people/swager-timothy&quot;&gt;Timothy Swager&lt;/a&gt;, the John D. MacArthur Professor in the Department of Chemistry at MIT &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.mit.edu/2017/future-of-sensory-technology-mit-nano-0522&quot;&gt;explains&lt;/a&gt;, “If you look at what’s happening with sensors, you’ll see that many different disciplines have to come together. Ubiquitous sensing has so many aspects — chemical, biological, physical, radiological. With all this sensing research going on, we need a place to coordinate our synergies.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mouser.com/applications/sensor-fusion-iot/&quot;&gt;Sensor fusion&lt;/a&gt; will bring the output of connected ecosystems closest to what a human brain does reading the environment by fusing together information from various sensory systems of the body. Granular streams of data from advanced sensory and tracking tech will be molded into a single model by advanced analytical capabilities of artificial intelligence running on the new generation of CPUs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-promise-of-smart-environments-and-the-internet-of-things-relies-on-robust-sensing-of-diverse-environmental-facets&quot;&gt;The promise of smart environments and the Internet of Things relies on robust sensing of diverse environmental facets.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Future Interfaces Group emphasizes that &lt;a href=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/564b5107e4b087849452ea4b/t/591c682917bffc66120bb75a/1495033927570/syntheticsensors.pdf&quot;&gt;the promise of smart environments and the Internet of Things relies on robust sensing of diverse environmental facets&lt;/a&gt;. Through what the Group calls Synthetic Sensors, raw sensor data can be virtualized into actionable feeds, whilst simultaneously mitigating immediate privacy issues. The Group deployed its system across many months and environments, the results of which demonstrated the versatility, accuracy, and potential of this approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A single room can have dozens of complex environmental facets worth sensing, ranging from “is the coffee brewed” to “is the tap dripping.” A single home might have hundreds of such facets, and an office building could have thousands. The cost of hundreds of physical sensors is significant, not including the even greater cost of deployment and maintenance. Moreover, extensively instrumenting an environment in this fashion will almost certainly carry an aesthetic and social cost.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;A lightweight, general-purpose sensing approach could overcome many of these issues. Ideally, a handful of “super” sensors could blanket an entire environment – one per room or less. To be minimally obtrusive, these sensors should be capable of sensing environmental facets indirectly (i.e., from afar) and be plug-and-play – foregoing batteries by using wall power, while still offering omniscience despite potential sub-optimal placement. Further, such a system should be able to answer questions of interest to users, abstracting raw sensor data (e.g., z-axis acceleration) into actionable feeds, encapsulating human semantics (e.g., a knock on the door), all while preserving occupant privacy.” – &lt;a href=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/564b5107e4b087849452ea4b/t/591c682917bffc66120bb75a/1495033927570/syntheticsensors.pdf&quot;&gt;Synthetic Sensors: Towards General-Purpose Sensing&lt;/a&gt;, by Gierad Laput, Yang Zhang, and Chris Harrison of Human-Computer Interaction Institute, Carnegie Mellon University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="IoT" /><category term="Internet of Things" /><summary type="html">Of all emerging technologies, executives believe the IoT will be the most important, ranking it above others such as artificial intelligence or robotics, Forbes reports. Some of the most recent estimates suggest that IoT technology revenues across 12 key smart city technologies and verticals will grow from around $25 billion in 2017 to $62 billion in 2026 at an average growth rate of 11%. But the successful real-world impact of IoT depends on enabling infrastructure, such as sensory and tracking technologies, advanced analytical capabilities running on the new generation of processing power.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily Review: Digitization of Global Trade with Blockchain Technology – IBM Leads the Way</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/daily-review-digitization-of-global-trade-with-blockchain-technology-ibm-leads-way/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily Review: Digitization of Global Trade with Blockchain Technology – IBM Leads the Way" /><published>2018-01-17T15:10:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-17T15:10:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/daily-review-digitization-of-global-trade-with-blockchain-technology-ibm-leads-way</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/daily-review-digitization-of-global-trade-with-blockchain-technology-ibm-leads-way/">&lt;p&gt;Being one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://letstalkpayments.com/8-game-changers-providing-blockchain-as-a-service-baas-platforms/&quot;&gt;game changers providing Blockchain-as-a-Service (BaaS) platforms&lt;/a&gt;, it comes as no surprise that IBM seeks to transform business models and enabling infrastructure in another industry – global trade. The right way to do it is to partner with the strongest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pick-1-ibm-forges-global-joint-venture-with-maersk-applying-blockchain-to-digitize-global-trade&quot;&gt;Pick #1. IBM Forges Global Joint Venture with Maersk Applying Blockchain to ‘Digitize’ Global Trade&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By applying the technology to digitize global trade processes, according to the joint venture partners a “new form of command and consent” can be introduced into the flow of information, thereby empowering multiple trading partners to collaborate and establishing a “single shared view” of a transaction – without compromising details, privacy or confidentiality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together with Maersk, the largest container ship and supply vessel operator in the world since 1996, the parties will use blockchain technology to power the new platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, they will employ other cloud-based open-source technologies including artificial intelligence (AI), Internet of Things (IoT) and analytics, delivered via IBM Services, in order to help companies move and track goods digitally across international borders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/rogeraitken/2018/01/16/ibm-forges-global-joint-venture-with-maersk-applying-blockchain-to-digitize-global-trade/#6eb2c428547e&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pick-2-how-home-depot-is-using-big-data-to-gain-a-big-advantage&quot;&gt;Pick #2. How Home Depot Is Using Big Data to Gain a Big Advantage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our data allows us to know our customer at a more individual level. Our targeting capability will help us get to them at the right place at the right time, and we aspire to have all of our messages be tailored to the audience… Customers will expect retailers to speak to them at an individual level. The world of traditional one-size-fits-all messaging is quickly falling behind us. We’ve got diverse customer groups. Here, you see an affluent baby boomer, a pro and a millennial who happens to be a new homeowner. The reality is… We regress to a lowest common denominator approach. We try to find the one message that somewhat appeals to all of them. But each of these customers has different needs and a different level of expertise.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home Depot’s marketing is so targeted that even when these individuals live on the same street in the same neighborhood and are watching the same game on television, they will see different ads. When customers from different areas of the country visit Home Depot’s home page, they will also see different products highlighted. But Home Depot has found ways to tailor marketing beyond just making it more personal for each consumer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things Home Depot is now experimenting with is weather-triggered ads. As Hoffman says, “These ads are only deployed and invested in when the weather is right.” Another thing the company is now deploying is local inventory ads, where ads will display depending on the inventory levels in a given area’s stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fool.com/investing/2018/01/15/how-home-depot-is-using-big-data-to-gain-a-big-adv.aspx&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pick-3-mobile-phone-payment-era-in-metro&quot;&gt;Pick #3. Mobile Phone Payment Era in Metro&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chinese passengers will be able to use their smartphones to pay for metro journeys from Saturday. However, foreign passengers will have to wait until June. After a two-month trial on the maglev line, payment by scanning a QR code will be available at all the city’s 389 metro stations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app offers two ways of paying. One is to deposit money, at least 10 yuan (US $1.5) through Alipay or UnionPay. Alternatively, the system will automatically take the fee from the user’s Alipay or bank account after each trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shine.cn/archive/metro/society/Mobile-phone-payment-era-in-Metro/shdaily.shtml&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pick-4-deutsche-bank-partners-with-tech-firm-to-offer-online-insurance-product&quot;&gt;Pick #4. Deutsche Bank Partners with Tech Firm to Offer Online Insurance Product&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deutsche Bank plans to establish its own insurance brokerage, operated by Friendsurance, to sell insurance through its online bank. It will not be just a platform to compare prices, nor will it be just a link to its partner, Friendsurance. Rather, it will perform the function of a traditional insurance broker advising the customer if a policy is a good fit or if there is a better alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://global.handelsblatt.com/finance/deutsche-bank-partners-with-tech-firm-to-offer-online-insurance-product-875857&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pick-5-blackhawk-network-to-expand-alipay-mobile-wallet-acceptance-to-select-top-retailers&quot;&gt;Pick #5. Blackhawk Network to Expand Alipay Mobile Wallet Acceptance to Select Top Retailers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blackhawk Network, a global financial technology company, and Alipay, a leading digital payment platform operated by Ant Financial Services Group, has partnered to expand Alipay’s mobile payment acceptance and engagement offerings to participating US retailers. Leveraging Blackhawk’s technology, the partnership will present an opportunity for Blackhawk’s network of retail partners to elect to engage with visiting Chinese travelers. Blackhawk intends to roll out the service in select participating retailers beginning January 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Approximately 4 million Chinese tourists visit North America every year. Many of those travelers are Alipay consumers already and are looking for the payment safety, convenience and efficiency they are accustomed to at home,” said Souheil Badran, President of Alipay Americas. “We partnered with Blackhawk for its robust network of top-tier retailer partners, its innovative solutions, and proprietary technology, and we are pleased to continue to provide Chinese travelers with a seamless shopping and payment experience in North America.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/blackhawk-network-to-expand-alipay-mobile-wallet-acceptance-to-select-top-retailers-300582401.html&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="fintech" /><category term="mobile wallets" /><category term="insurtech" /><category term="blockchain" /><category term="big data" /><category term="payments" /><category term="blockchain-as-a-service" /><category term="BaaS" /><category term="mobile payments" /><category term="insurance" /><summary type="html">Being one of the game changers providing Blockchain-as-a-Service (BaaS) platforms, it comes as no surprise that IBM seeks to transform business models and enabling infrastructure in another industry – global trade. The right way to do it is to partner with the strongest.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">8 Game Changers Providing Blockchain-as-a-Service (BaaS) Platforms</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/8-game-changers-providing-blockchain-as-a-service-baas-platforms/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="8 Game Changers Providing Blockchain-as-a-Service (BaaS) Platforms" /><published>2018-01-16T16:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-16T16:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/8-game-changers-providing-blockchain-as-a-service-baas-platforms</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/8-game-changers-providing-blockchain-as-a-service-baas-platforms/">&lt;p&gt;With an increasing number of enterprises expressing interest in distributed ledger technology, tech companies are rushing to meet the demand. To democratize blockchain technology, Microsoft, IBM, Deloitte, and now Baidu and Tencent, have developed their own platforms offering blockchain-as-a-Service (BaaS). Let’s look at three examples of BaaS solutions taking enterprise-grade experimentation with blockchain to a whole new level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;baidu-blockchain-open-platform&quot;&gt;Baidu Blockchain Open Platform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coindesk.com/search-giant-baidu-launches-blockchain-as-a-service-platform/&quot;&gt;Coindesk&lt;/a&gt;, on January 12, Chinese web search giant &lt;a href=&quot;https://chain.baidu.com/&quot;&gt;Baidu has launched its own Blockchain-as-a-Service (BaaS) platform&lt;/a&gt;. Based on technology developed by Baidu, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://chain.baidu.com/&quot;&gt;open platform&lt;/a&gt; sets out to provide the most “user-friendly” blockchain service. &lt;a href=&quot;https://trust.baidu.com/vstar/official/index/&quot;&gt;Baidu Trust&lt;/a&gt; allows the conducting and tracing of transactions; it can be applied in various use cases, including digital currency, digital billing, bank credit management, insurance management financial auditing, and more. The company says the technology has already been applied in asset securitization &amp;amp; exchange, and claims it has contributed to the “first asset-backed securities exchange products using blockchain technology in China.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;blockchain-cloud-service-by-oracle&quot;&gt;Blockchain Cloud Service by Oracle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2017, Oracle &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oracle.com/corporate/pressrelease/oow17-oracle-launches-blockchain-cloud-service-100217.html&quot;&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt; its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oracle.com/cloud/blockchain/index.html&quot;&gt;Oracle Blockchain Cloud Service&lt;/a&gt;, an offering that is part of Oracle’s comprehensive Platform-as-a-Service (PaaS) portfolio. The enterprise-grade distributed ledger cloud platform helps customers increase business velocity, create new revenue streams, and reduce cost and risk by securely extending ERP, supply chain, and other enterprise SaaS and on-premises applications to drive tamper-resistant transactions on a trusted business network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oracle Blockchain Cloud Service enables customers to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Deliver business results with the ability to rapidly onboard and easily scale the network participants globally, while ensuring that operations run continually with resilience, high availability, and autonomous recoverability.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Accelerate Innovation with Oracle Cloud Applications by extending enterprise boundaries to reduce friction in existing business processes and enable new business models and opportunity to access untapped revenue streams. The Applications Integration toolkit provides integrated applications, sample code, templates and design patterns to accelerate the integration of blockchain applications to Oracle SaaS and on-premises applications suites.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Speed up business processes through trusted real-time information sharing across existing Oracle ERP Cloud, Oracle SCM Cloud, Netsuite SuiteCloud Platform or custom blockchain application integrations.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Reduce risk, complexity, and increase efficiency by securely automating cross-organization transactions, and providing reliable sharing of information both inside and outside the enterprise boundary. Combined, these can help reduce transaction costs, mitigate security and privacy risks for enterprises, and simplify compliance and audits.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the press release, Oracle plans to offer Oracle Blockchain Cloud Service as part of Oracle Platform for Open Banking, and provide seamless connectivity between Oracle FLEXCUBE and other banks to enable greater security, scalability, and transparency in the information exchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hewlett-packard-enterprise-blockchain-as-a-service&quot;&gt;Hewlett-Packard Enterprise Blockchain-as-a-Service&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In November 2017, Hewlett-Packard &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.hpe.com/hewlett-packard-enterprise-introduces-blockchain-as-a-service-solution-for-enterprises/&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; the first product in the HPE Mission Critical Blockchain family. Mission Critical Distributed Ledger Technology (DLT) is a solution that enables customers to run distributed ledger workloads on the highest availability enterprise platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the official press release, the Mission Critical DLT solution is a part of HPE’s overall approach to bring an enterprise-grade capability to blockchain workloads. The solution is offered on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hpe.com/us/en/servers/nonstop.html&quot;&gt;HPE Integrity NonStop platforms&lt;/a&gt;, which process two out of every three credit card transactions in the world. It was developed in partnership with enterprise software firm R3, integrating the company’s distributed ledger technology with HPE’s Mission Critical platform. This combination enables customers to execute distributed-ledger workloads in environments that demand 100% fault tolerance at mission-critical levels and ensures massive scalability to grow with the business as well as SQL integration with legacy systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ibm-blockchain-platform&quot;&gt;IBM Blockchain Platform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://console.bluemix.net/catalog/services/blockchain&quot;&gt;The IBM Blockchain Platform&lt;/a&gt; is a fully integrated blockchain platform designed to accelerate the development, governing, and operation of a multi-institution business network. The platform allows to develop an application, govern and operate the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Enterprise Membership Plan includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Access to the network’s transaction ordering service&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A highly available certificate authority&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A network peer, running in a highly secure environment, isolated from other members’ environments (additional peers can be purchased for high availability)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Coming soon: Cryptographic keys stored in a hardware security module (HSM); certified to FIPS 140-2 Level 4 – the highest in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Enterprise Plan meets production requirements including security and performance for regulated industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IBM Blockchain Platform is not the only way IBM is involved in powering distributed networks. In February 2016, IBM made nearly 44,000 lines of code available to the Linux Foundation’s open-source &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hyperledger.org/&quot;&gt;Hyperledger Project&lt;/a&gt; to help developers easily build secure distributed ledgers that can be used to exchange almost anything of value. Launching the new service, IBM was intended to help developers create and manage blockchain networks to power a new class of distributed ledger applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IBM has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www-03.ibm.com/press/us/en/pressrelease/49029.wss&quot;&gt;listed&lt;/a&gt; unique capabilities the new service brings, among which are pluggable architecture to allow developers use software modules (consensus module for example) that best suits their needs, a new consensus algorithm developed by IBM Research tailored to specific blockchain use cases, advanced identity management built with the latest cryptography, smart contracts that can be written in popular programming languages such as Java or Golang and executed in containers, and fine-grained privacy and confidentiality control, which allows authors of smart contracts to precisely specify both who can view them and who can execute them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;microsoft-blockchain-on-azure&quot;&gt;Microsoft Blockchain on Azure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/solutions/blockchain/&quot;&gt;Microsoft Blockchain on Azure&lt;/a&gt; is an application development platform from Microsoft with a set of solution templates that deploy and configure client’s choice of blockchain network with minimal Azure and blockchain knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a handful of user inputs and a simple single-click deployment through the Azure portal, clients can provision a fully configured blockchain network topology in minutes, using Microsoft Azure compute, networking, and storage services across the globe. Microsoft has automated these time-consuming pieces to allow clients to focus on building out scenarios and applications. Clients are only charged for the underlying infrastructure resources consumed, such as compute, storage, and networking. There are no incremental charges for the solution itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The platform has two software plans:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethereum Consortium Blockchain: This solution deploys an Ethereum simulated multi-member network, consisting of a set of load-balanced transaction nodes with which an application or user can interact to submit transactions and a set of mining nodes to record transactions. It can take between 5-20 minutes to provision, depending on the size of the network. Once complete, through the administrator web page, you can configure additional Ethereum accounts to get started with smart contract, and eventually application, development. The URL for the administrator web page is the first output of the deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sap-cloud-platform-blockchain-service&quot;&gt;SAP Cloud Platform Blockchain Service&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May 2017, SAP &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.sap.com/sapphire-now-sap-cloud-platform-blockchain-service/&quot;&gt;revealed&lt;/a&gt; its cloud-based blockchain service &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.sap.com/sapphire-now-new-sap-leonardo-digitally-transform-at-scale/&quot;&gt;SAP Leonardo&lt;/a&gt;. With SAP Leonardo, SAP announced a digital innovation system that meaningfully integrates next-generation technologies to help its customers redefine their business – including ready-to-use blockchain technology and its SAP Cloud Platform Blockchain service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SAP Cloud Platform Blockchain service allows for an easy setup and management of blockchain nodes. This will help customers get started with an example application to examine the potential of blockchain technology. Interested companies can begin by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sap.com/cmp/dg/crm-xm17-gtm-dsc-bc/index.html&quot;&gt;registering for SAP’s co-innovation program&lt;/a&gt; to collaborate with the company and build first solutions together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The integration of additional powerful technologies within SAP Leonardo complements the opportunities of blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stratis&quot;&gt;Stratis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stratisplatform.com/&quot;&gt;Stratis&lt;/a&gt; offers simple and affordable end-to-end solutions for development, testing, and deployment of native C# blockchain applications on the .Net framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Development. The Stratis Development Platform allows businesses and organizations to develop blockchain applications in C# utilizing the Microsoft .NET Framework. The company can assist in defining blockchain strategy and in integrating its solutions and capabilities according to business requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testing. The Cloud Stratis platform allows developers to quickly provision full blockchain nodes to test their applications. The Cloud Stratis platform can also provision blockchain nodes for Bitcoin, Ethereum, and Bitshares, if the developer wants to develop an application specifically for one of these existing blockchains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deployment. The Cloud Stratis platform allows businesses and organizations to test and deploy their blockchain-based applications in the cloud, without having to maintain the network or full clients themselves. The implementation of the blockchain can be tailored to their needs and accessed via lite clients or APIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stratis service partners include Microsoft Azure, Ledger, Poloniex, Changelly, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tencent-in-development&quot;&gt;Tencent (in development)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coindesk.com/internet-giant-tencent-blockchain-platform/&quot;&gt;Coindesk&lt;/a&gt; reported in April 2017, Tencent is building a suite of blockchain services, detailing the plans in a new white paper. The firm is planning to use the technology to offer digital asset management, authentication and “shared economies,” among others services. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://trustsql.qq.com/chain_oss/index_gw.html&quot;&gt;platform&lt;/a&gt; called “TrustSQL” is envisioned as a three-part system, incorporating the core chain layer, a product and service layer, and an application layer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In statements, Tencent said that it would leverage its technological resources to push the platform and that it sees the project as an open-ended one that encourages collaboration with other firms.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blockchain" /><category term="distributed ledger technology" /><category term="distributed systems" /><category term="blockchain-as-a-service" /><category term="BaaS" /><category term="SaaS" /><summary type="html">With an increasing number of enterprises expressing interest in distributed ledger technology, tech companies are rushing to meet the demand. To democratize blockchain technology, Microsoft, IBM, Deloitte, and now Baidu and Tencent, have developed their own platforms offering blockchain-as-a-Service (BaaS). Let’s look at three examples of BaaS solutions taking enterprise-grade experimentation with blockchain to a whole new level.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Daily Review: Lessons from the Most Digitally Advanced Country in the World</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/daily-review-lessons-from-most-digitally-advanced-country-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Daily Review: Lessons from the Most Digitally Advanced Country in the World" /><published>2018-01-16T15:30:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-16T15:30:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/daily-review-lessons-from-most-digitally-advanced-country-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/daily-review-lessons-from-most-digitally-advanced-country-world/">&lt;p&gt;There are at least &lt;a href=&quot;https://letstalkpayments.com/9-reasons-to-launch-expand-startup-in-estonia/&quot;&gt;nine reasons to launch and expand a business in this European country&lt;/a&gt;. This country is a rare example of how a little nation relentlessly completes with its own legacy to gallop ahead of the world and build the government of the future in the modern day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pick-1-lessons-from-the-most-digitally-advanced-country-in-the-world&quot;&gt;Pick #1. Lessons from the Most Digitally Advanced Country in the World&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Estonia received a lot of press coverage last year for our e-Residency program, which is just one of the ideas that we created. I am very proud of the real-time economy and the no-legacy policy what we put in place. All the architecture in Estonia is connected. It is very easy to combine data sets and information from different registries because everybody uses the same identifiers for data. The trust between the companies, the people, and the government is so strong that, for example, companies are willing to share their business-to-business data with the government monthly. The government knows who dealt with whom, allowing them to better protect the market and enabling a full understanding of what happens in the economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For example, how are gas industries doing, how is machinery doing, how is one region doing compared to another region, how much capital moves from one area to another area. We can track this in real-time. It is the future of governments.” – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/taavi-kotka-26335b33/&quot;&gt;Taavi Kotka&lt;/a&gt;, Head of Estonia E-Residency Council, Enterprise Estonia; Special Advisor to VP Andrus Ansip, European Commission; VP of Sales, Plumbr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/peterhigh/2018/01/15/lessons-from-the-most-digitally-advanced-country-in-the-world/#722f3b1b21ac&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pick-2-apple-xerox-ibm-and-fumbling-the-future&quot;&gt;Pick #2. Apple, Xerox, IBM, and Fumbling The Future&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amazing thing is that the IBM researchers understood the importance of hypermedia well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In the context of a global multi-media information utility, the hypermedia concept takes on an enhanced significance in that global hypermedia links may be created to allow users to navigate through and create new views and relations from separate, distributed databases. A professional composing a hyper-document would imbed in it direct hyperlinks to the works he means to cite, rather than painfully typing in references. ‘Readers’ would then be able to directly select these links and see the real things instead of having to chase them through references. The set of all databases maintained on-line would thus form a hypernet of information on which the user’s workstation would be a powerful window.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it was Berners-Lee, not IBM, that successfully translated his vision into a viable product (or, more accurately, three standards that spawned millions of successful products). Why? Because he looked at the future through a different lens than IBM’s (or AOL’s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Berners-Lee’s vision did not focus on the question of how you deliver information – the network – but on the question of how you organize and share it. This, as it turned out, was the right path to realizing the visions of e-books, a flood of worthless information, and the elimination of all kinds of intermediaries. And because this road was taken by Berners-Lee and others, starting with Mosaic (the first successful browser), information became free and its creation shifted in a big way from large, established media companies to individuals and small “new media” ventures. Because this road was taken, IT innovation in the last 30 years has been mainly in the consumer space, and the market for information services has been almost entirely consumer-oriented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/gilpress/2018/01/14/apple-xerox-ibm-and-fumbling-the-future/#a4489b218b3f&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pick-3-how-banking-as-a-platform-propels-cross-river-bank&quot;&gt;Pick #3. How Banking-as-a-Platform Propels Cross River Bank&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nair: Which areas or segments in the FinTech industry do you believe have exciting growth potential?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gade: I would say regulatory technology, even though it’s been a bit of a buzzword lately. Regulatory technology is what will enable the various financial companies to continue to innovate within the confines of regulation because, at the end of the day, the biggest hindrance to innovation has been the manual verification of transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://knowledge.wharton.upenn.edu/article/banking-platform-propels-cross-river-bank/&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="e-Residency" /><category term="hypernet" /><category term="banking-as-a-platform" /><category term="banking" /><category term="compliance" /><category term="regulatory technology" /><category term="regtech" /><summary type="html">There are at least nine reasons to launch and expand a business in this European country. This country is a rare example of how a little nation relentlessly completes with its own legacy to gallop ahead of the world and build the government of the future in the modern day.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">FinTech &amp;amp; Beyond: More Than a Technology Shift</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fintech-and-beyond-more-than-a-technology-shift-video/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FinTech &amp; Beyond: More Than a Technology Shift" /><published>2018-01-15T17:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-15T17:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fintech-and-beyond-more-than-a-technology-shift-video</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fintech-and-beyond-more-than-a-technology-shift-video/">&lt;p&gt;FinTech and new ways of operating money have brought a significant paradigm shift in our lives. As technology changes, it affects our behavior. Kai Ren, Former VP of Goldman Sachs in New York, currently the CEO and Co-founder of AFA Finance, describes how people who have gone through the progress of technology can manage such shift through a mindset change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XpefSB0aXAg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fintech &amp;amp; Beyond: More Than a Technology Shift, Kai Ren, TEDxTianshanPark&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="fintech" /><summary type="html">FinTech and new ways of operating money have brought a significant paradigm shift in our lives. As technology changes, it affects our behavior. Kai Ren, Former VP of Goldman Sachs in New York, currently the CEO and Co-founder of AFA Finance, describes how people who have gone through the progress of technology can manage such shift through a mindset change.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Accessible Credit Will Not Lift Individuals From Poverty, Financial Education Will</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/accessible-credit-will-not-lift-individuals-from-poverty-financial-education-will/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Accessible Credit Will Not Lift Individuals From Poverty, Financial Education Will" /><published>2018-01-13T03:07:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-13T03:07:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/accessible-credit-will-not-lift-individuals-from-poverty-financial-education-will</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/accessible-credit-will-not-lift-individuals-from-poverty-financial-education-will/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;give-a-man-a-fish-and-you-feed-him-for-a-day-teach-a-man-to-fish-and-you-feed-him-for-a-lifetime&quot;&gt;Give a man a fish, and you feed him for a day. Teach a man to fish, and you feed him for a lifetime.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Successfully and sustainably scaling a financial product/service is tied to the ability to educate individuals on how they can use acquired access to money to build their future wealth and overcome unforeseen financial challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of lending startups with genuinely noble intentions to empower financially challenged ones have a dangerous misconception about their target audience – a belief that simply giving money to the poor solves the issue of poverty. The only barrier modern non-institutional lenders are trying to overcome is to deliver the money to the potential consumer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having money, however, does not solve the core issue – lack of financial literacy among individuals that have been systematically excluded from the formal financial system and, unfortunately, are not always empowered with a knowledge on how to use the money to lift own family from poverty. Obviously, immediate basic needs are as far as the credit goes (which is absolutely understandable). After spending the obtained credit, financially challenged families are forced to find a source of credit to pay back the first credit. It creates a perpetual vicious circle that further diminishes chances to obtain financial freedom and build long-term resilience. What &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alterinter.org/spip.php?article3582&quot;&gt;started as a groundbreaking progress to lift a nation from poverty&lt;/a&gt; proved to be &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hindustantimes.com/india/microfinance-has-failed-in-india-jairam-ramesh/story-4Hb8zjxPeVYI1gxmyUAfFO.html&quot;&gt;a more complex issue&lt;/a&gt; than an extension of credit, leading to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://thewire.in/18937/why-microfinance-is-becoming-a-bad-word-all-over-again/&quot;&gt;regress for the industry and for the poor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-educated-customer-is-the-best-customer&quot;&gt;The educated customer is the best customer.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Financial institutions, while certainly more selective with their customers, have been eager to share knowledge in attempts to promote financial literacy for an important reason – &lt;a href=&quot;https://letstalkpayments.com/banking-is-partnership-and-perfect-partner-can-only-be-nurtured-not-acquired/&quot;&gt;banking of the future will not be a customer acquisition matter, but a lifelong journey of nurturing the perfect customer&lt;/a&gt;. International bodies understand the need to educate individuals on wise financial behavior while developing and delivering suits of services that will anticipate and meet the needs of their customers at every point in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fed has been loyally developing its own &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.federalreserveeducation.org/&quot;&gt;educational initiative&lt;/a&gt; since August 2003. Recognizing that there is a lot to learn about money, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.minneapolisfed.org/publications/community-dividend/fed-launches-national-initiative-to-promote-financial-education&quot;&gt;the Federal Reserve System has launched an initiative to promote financial education&lt;/a&gt; with an aim to connect consumers with the knowledge and resources they need to make informed financial decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, the World Federation of Exchanges, which represents public markets around the world, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.world-exchanges.org/home/index.php/news/world-exchange-news/world-exchanges-launch-global-financial-education-literacy-initiative&quot;&gt;launched a new global industry initiative to promote financial education and entrepreneurial skills among school children and university students&lt;/a&gt;, following an overwhelming response from its members to join a new study group on the topic. At that time, 31 exchange and clearing house members of WFE have joined the initiative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of 2017, in collaboration with globally renowned institutions and organizations, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbva.com/en/bbva-launches-center-financial-education-capability/&quot;&gt;BBVA launched a Center for Financial Education and Capability&lt;/a&gt;. The Center was launched with a goal of promoting financial knowledge and helping people acquire the skills that allow them to improve their lives and access better opportunities. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbvaedufin.com/&quot;&gt;Center for Financial Education and Capability&lt;/a&gt; is an online platform that seeks to channel all this acquired experience to promote progress and equal opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BBVA has partnered with internationally renowned organizations in financial education and inclusion in this initiative. This includes the World Bank, the Institute of International Finance (IIF), the European Banking Federation, the Inter-American Development Bank (IDB), the Ibero-American General Secretariat, the Global Financial Literacy Excellence Center (GFLEC), the Centre for Financial Inclusion, as well as a wide range of institutions from the public sector, specialized associations, consumers groups, and NGOs, who share their knowledge and experience through the Advisory Board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2017, Treasurer &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.treasurerlynnfitch.ms.gov/Pages/default.aspx&quot;&gt;Lynn Fitch&lt;/a&gt;, Attorney General &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ago.state.ms.us/&quot;&gt;Jim Hood&lt;/a&gt;, the Mississippi Council on Economic Education (&lt;a href=&quot;http://mscee.org/&quot;&gt;MCEE&lt;/a&gt;), and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://extension.msstate.edu/&quot;&gt;Mississippi State University Extension Service&lt;/a&gt; came together for &lt;a href=&quot;https://mississippitoday.org/2017/09/22/treasurer-attorney-general-launch-2-5-million-financial-literacy-program/&quot;&gt;a new financial literacy effort&lt;/a&gt; that will be taking place in schools and communities over the next two years thanks to $2.5 million from the state’s legal settlements with three credit rating agencies and two financial institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program, called &lt;em&gt;Making Sense of Your Dollars and Cents,&lt;/em&gt; will focus on expanding teacher training from kindergarten through high school levels, provide incentives to teachers and schools to incorporate financial education into their students’ studies, support teachers with learning experiences for their students in and out of the classroom, and finally, build a financial wellness network and implement financial coaching through community leaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capital One runs its own financial &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.capitalone.com/financial-education/financial-literacy-programs/&quot;&gt;literacy programs&lt;/a&gt;. In partnership with the National Association of Collegiate Directors of Athletics (NACDA), Capital One launched &lt;a href=&quot;http://3blmedia.com/News/CSR/Capital-One-Fiscal-U-Program-Teaches-Financial-Management-Skills-Student-Athletes-Program&quot;&gt;Capital One Fiscal U&lt;/a&gt; to provide student-athletes with personal finance basics in areas including saving, budgeting, credit &amp;amp; debt management, and investing. This program is now being offered to more than 1,600 colleges and universities across the nation as part of their student-athlete program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;American Bankers Association (ABA) has similar &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aba.com/Engagement/Pages/financialed.aspx&quot;&gt;initiatives&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Teach Children to Save, Safe Banking for Seniors, Get Smart About Credit&lt;/em&gt;, and even a contest called &lt;em&gt;Lights Camera Save!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Financial capability and education provide a foundation for personal prosperity and build strong communities by ensuring that individuals have the knowledge and resources they need to make informed decisions at every stage of life,” – TD Bank is also among the institutions with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tdbank.com/community/financial_literacy.html&quot;&gt;resources dedicated to financial education&lt;/a&gt;. Moreover, the TD Charitable Foundation’s Non-Profit Training Resource Fund provides donations to eligible organizations to support employee job training, education, and professional development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;access-to-credit-without-education-can-have-an-adverse-effect-on-the-poor&quot;&gt;Access to credit without education can have an adverse effect on the poor.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Financial education and access to knowledge about productive money management is a vital element that will differentiate successful lending businesses from unsuccessful ones. A study called *Microfinance for Poverty Alleviation: Do Transnational Initiatives Overlook Fundamental Questions of Competition and Intermediation?*published by the United Nations in 2017 emphasizes that poverty alleviation required asset accumulation through entrepreneurial activities. Loans to micro-entrepreneurs help people to accumulate assets, while non-productive loans merely help people to consume more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accessible consumer credit/microcredit, cannot alone alleviate poverty. Professionals have been studying the effect of microcredit on the well-being of financially challenged individuals and families for a very long time. Results of a study called &lt;em&gt;Can Microcredit Worsen Poverty? Cases of Exacerbated Poverty in Bangladesh,&lt;/em&gt; published back in 2011, emphasize cases when microcredit exacerbates poverty in developing countries. This study examined cases in Bangladesh where microcredit has actually worsened poverty among borrowers and investigated the underlying reasons for this adverse trend. The results revealed that microcredit can exacerbate poverty in four interrelated circumstances. Researchers argued that households living in extreme conditions of poverty that possess minimal or no surplus financial capacity to cope with contingencies are prone to adverse effects of microcredit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The findings of a study performed over a decade ago, and even the most recent one, are especially relevant today because technology made it possible for a large number of non-institutional lenders to extend access to easy credit to underbanked/unbanked without heavy educational primer. The result of such approach is likely to become crippling for families who use those services as the last resort, and for the companies that do not manage to help borrowers to use the money wisely.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="financial education" /><category term="financial inclusion" /><category term="financial services" /><category term="lending" /><category term="microcredit" /><category term="microfinance" /><category term="education" /><summary type="html">Give a man a fish, and you feed him for a day. Teach a man to fish, and you feed him for a lifetime.</summary></entry></feed>